wp-events-plugin.com 2018-12-23

# Privacy Policy - Events Manager for WordPress

_Last Updated : May 25 2018_

## Who we are

Events Manager and Events Manager Pro is an events management plugin for WordPress. Events Manager and Events Manager Pro is wholly owned by Pixelite SL, a provider of software solutions and services based in Andorra.

We respect the privacy of all our users and therefore collect and store only the data we require to provide our services to you, and ensure is stored in a safe manner ensuring your privacy.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Customers

While using our Site, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact, identify you and meet contractual and fiscal obligations. Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to your name, email and billing address.

We use the information we collect about you in the following ways:

  * To respond to any requests from you regarding sales and support.
  * To contact you regarding any agreements or accepted terms that you may have with Pixelite SL
  * To provide you with marketing emails, special offers, or newsletters.
  * To find and prevent fraud.
  * To carry out other purposes as disclosed to you through the Website, or found in terms or an agreement between you and Pixelite SL.
  * Process for other purposes for which we obtain your consent.

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

Like many site operators, we collect information that your browser sends whenever you visit our Site (“Log Data”). This Log Data may include information such as your computer’s Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, browser version, the pages of our Site that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages and other statistics.

We use Google Analytics to help us understand how our customers use the site — you can read more about how Google uses your Personal Information here: https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/. You can also opt-out of Google Analytics here: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.

We also use JetPack statistics to monitor site usage, you can see their privacy policy here – https://automattic.com/privacy/

### Data collected by the Events Manager Pro plugin and other commercially available plugins we provide

When you install our plugin on your site, this plugin will send your website domain, IP address and license key for the purposes of verifying your license validity. We do not collect any site or personal data, and should we ever do so in the future, we will explicitly ask for your consent and explain what data we will collect.

## Who we share your data with

We do not and will never sell or transfer your data for reasons other than providing you with a better service on our own websites. All third party services have their own privacy policies in accordance to European GDPR laws. We use various services in order to achieve this including:

Braintree – We use Braintree to process credit card payments and store payment information securely. During checkout, payment information is transferred to Braintree and not stored on our site.

PayPal – We also use PayPal for payment processing, you must have a PayPal account to use their service, who have their own privacy policy and terms of service.

Amazon Services – We use Amazon CDN services to serve our website content faster around the world, which may collect your IP address and browser information when accessing that content.

Slack – We use slack for internal communication between our employees and may therefore need to reference you, the customer, in order to provide contracted support services.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website, we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile, including name, email, billing address and any websites licensed to use our software. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## How we protect your data and what data breach procedures we have in place

We protect customer data with the following site features:

  * We are entirely using SSL/HTTPS throughout all our sites. This encrypts our user communications with the servers so personal identifiable information is never captured by third parties without authorization.
  * We use firewalls and malware scanners to prevent unauthorized access to your data.
  * Databases are sanitized (actual user personal details are removed) before deploying to development or testing environment.

In case of a data breach, System administrators will immediately go through affected users and will attempt to reset passwords if needed after informing the user.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us.

You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes. In short, we cannot erase data that is vital to you being our customer (i.e. basic account information like an email address and billing address for fiscal purposes).

You can request this information or erasure by contacting us [here](https://wp-events-plugin.com/contact-us/).
